# Kacie Hatley

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

#### CONTACT

704-9

704-985-2663



kaciehatley@gmail.com



Charlotte, NC



Linkedin.com/in/kacie-hatley

## EDUCATION

# FULL STACK DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP

Continuing Education UNC Charlotte Oct 2019 – Apr 2020

#### **ELEMENTARY EDUCATION**

Bachelors of Science Wingate University Aug 2013 – May 2016

# KEY SKILLS

- Bug-Fixing and Troubleshooting: Skilled in methodically testing/identifying issues within front and back-end code
- Web applications: Created numerous sleek, full-stack web applications by integrating a wide variety of technologies
- Video Production: Attended video production training through North Carolina State University; trained local businesses and non-profits in video production and video marketing
- Written Materials: Published numerous articles on the North Carolina State University website; proofed and edited written materials for coworkers and supervisor
- Public Speaking: Delivered formal presentations to multiple grant allocations committees, steering committees, and public officials

#### PROFILE

Entry-level, full-stack developer with 4 years of professional experience as a leader in the field of education. Well-known amongst colleagues for strong work ethic, creativity, and adaptability. Eager to find creative solutions to complex problems. Currently in search of entry-level internship or full-time position—frontend, back-end, and full stack.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Proficient:** HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Materialize, JavaScript, jQuery, Express, ORM, Git Version Control

Experienced: OOJS, Python, TDD, MongoDB, Mongoose

#### **PROJECTS**

#### All Booked Library Management System (2020)

https://cryptic-chamber-77839.herokuapp.com/ Engineering Lead

- Designed website layout and created front-end using handlebars
- Examined documentation for Google Books API and created ajax calls to retrieve and populate data dynamically
- Created API routes via Node.js ORM, Sequelize
- Facilitated client-server systems using REST APIs

### **Simple Eats Recipe Finder** (2019)

https://kaciehatley.github.io/simple-eats/index2.html Front-End Engineer

- Dynamically created recipe cards using data retrieved from Spoonacular
  API
- Used local storage to create and render user's grocery list

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

4-H Youth Development Agent

NC State University | Albemarle, NC | June 2017-Present

- Led afterschool Python coding club for middle-school aged youth
- Taught computational thinking skills via Scratch and promoted software/web development as a career in STEM classes throughout community
- Designed print & online resources that have been used statewide (using tools such as Adobe and Canva)
- Increased programs contacts by 700%, outreach by 56%, and social media following by over 200% within first 18 months in position.
- Supervised over 150 volunteers by developing trainings, providing support, and evaluating performance

#### Classroom Teacher

Stanly County Schools | Norwood, NC | July 2016-June 2017

- Trained staff in various technologies to enhance classroom instruction
- Streamlined lesson-planning by organizing grade levels' Google Drive